{
  "a1": "More studies needs to be done.  I support programs that will teach students competency and able to compete with students around the world.",
  "a10": "Build the Wall, send National Guards to the border states and arrest the drug pushers!  Do Not catch and release !  Support President Trump on this issue!",
  "a11": "There's going to be income inequality no matter what !  Income should be based on merits, educational level and experience , not on gender!",
  "a12": "More research needs to be done in this area.",
  "a2": "Governor Hogan's plan is my plan!  He needs senators to work with him, not against him!",
  "a3": "No, but for medicinal purposes, yes ! Also those who are at the end of their life, should be allowed to use it .",
  "a4": "Pig farmers and chicken farmers need to cooperate with the crabbers and Waterman on preserving the health of the Chesapeake Bay with the help of PA, VA and NJ .  It is the body of water used by these neighboring states.",
  "a5": "Support Governor Hogan's plan !",
  "a6": "Identify competent candidates to run as Mayor, not just based on the color of the skin!  Ask State for help and use national guards just like Governor Hogan did !",
  "a7": "Maryland is open for business ! Support the Governor's plan !  MD was 47th in business growth and now we're Number 2 !  Continue with the Governor's program of pro growth !",
  "a8": "This case is in the Supreme Court to be determined this coming June . No one party ought to carve out areas to benefit the party in control! Watch the Supreme Court decision !",
  "a9": "Obey the law !  No need to create more laws just because some illegal immigrants or would-be terrorists break the law, the police need to enforce the law !  Two officers were shot to death because the law breakers want to harm these officers.  ENFORCE the law and the media should report honest and true news rather than fake news !",
  "background": "US Dept. of Education  Montgomery College faculty MCPS Teacher",
  "directory": "content/state-senate/district-17",
  "district": 17,
  "education": "MA , BA IN Education  Taft Fellow in Politicsl Science",
  "filename": "josephine-j-wang.md",
  "full-name": "Josephine J. Wang",
  "jurisdiction": "Montgomery County",
  "last-name": "Wang",
  "party": "Republican",
  "q1": "Do you support the findings of the Commission on Innovation and Excellence in Education? Are you committed to funding associated reforms, and if so, how?",
  "q10": "What strategy would you adopt to address the opioid addiction and overdose crisis?",
  "q11": "What if anything should the state do to address income inequality?",
  "q12": "Do the state’s Public Information Act and open meetings laws adequately ensure Marylanders’ ability to exercise oversight of the government?",
  "q2": "Is Maryland’s transportation spending appropriately balanced between roads and transit? Does the state have the resources to meet its transportation needs? With the cancellation of the Red Line and the advent of BaltimoreLink, is the Baltimore region adequately served by transit?",
  "q3": "Do you support the legalization of recreational marijuana?",
  "q4": "At a time when the federal government’s commitment to Chesapeake Bay restoration is questionable, what new steps should Maryland take to protect this resource?",
  "q5": "What steps should Maryland take to ensure the broadest possible access to affordable health care?",
  "q6": "What role should the state play in helping Baltimore address violent crime?",
  "q7": "How would you characterize Maryland’s business climate? What can the state do to foster the creation of more family-supporting jobs?",
  "q8": "Do you support the creation of a non-partisan, independent body to draw legislative and congressional district maps after each census?",
  "q9": "Does the Law Enforcement Officers Bill of Rights adequately balance protections for police and the public? Should it be changed, and if so, how?",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Do you support the findings of the Commission on Innovation and Excellence in Education? Are you committed to funding associated reforms, and if so, how?",
      "answer": "More studies needs to be done.  I support programs that will teach students competency and able to compete with students around the world.",
      "shortname": "Kirwan"
    },
    {
      "question": "Is Maryland’s transportation spending appropriately balanced between roads and transit? Does the state have the resources to meet its transportation needs? With the cancellation of the Red Line and the advent of BaltimoreLink, is the Baltimore region adequately served by transit?",
      "answer": "Governor Hogan's plan is my plan!  He needs senators to work with him, not against him!",
      "shortname": "Transportation"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you support the legalization of recreational marijuana?",
      "answer": "No, but for medicinal purposes, yes ! Also those who are at the end of their life, should be allowed to use it .",
      "shortname": "Marijuana"
    },
    {
      "question": "At a time when the federal government’s commitment to Chesapeake Bay restoration is questionable, what new steps should Maryland take to protect this resource?",
      "answer": "Pig farmers and chicken farmers need to cooperate with the crabbers and Waterman on preserving the health of the Chesapeake Bay with the help of PA, VA and NJ .  It is the body of water used by these neighboring states.",
      "shortname": "Chesapeake Bay"
    },
    {
      "question": "What steps should Maryland take to ensure the broadest possible access to affordable health care?",
      "answer": "Support Governor Hogan's plan !",
      "shortname": "Health Care"
    },
    {
      "question": "What role should the state play in helping Baltimore address violent crime?",
      "answer": "Identify competent candidates to run as Mayor, not just based on the color of the skin!  Ask State for help and use national guards just like Governor Hogan did !",
      "shortname": "Crime"
    },
    {
      "question": "How would you characterize Maryland’s business climate? What can the state do to foster the creation of more family-supporting jobs?",
      "answer": "Maryland is open for business ! Support the Governor's plan !  MD was 47th in business growth and now we're Number 2 !  Continue with the Governor's program of pro growth !",
      "shortname": "Business Climate"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you support the creation of a non-partisan, independent body to draw legislative and congressional district maps after each census?",
      "answer": "This case is in the Supreme Court to be determined this coming June . No one party ought to carve out areas to benefit the party in control! Watch the Supreme Court decision !",
      "shortname": "Redistricting"
    },
    {
      "question": "Does the Law Enforcement Officers Bill of Rights adequately balance protections for police and the public? Should it be changed, and if so, how?",
      "answer": "Obey the law !  No need to create more laws just because some illegal immigrants or would-be terrorists break the law, the police need to enforce the law !  Two officers were shot to death because the law breakers want to harm these officers.  ENFORCE the law and the media should report honest and true news rather than fake news !",
      "shortname": "LEOBR"
    },
    {
      "question": "What strategy would you adopt to address the opioid addiction and overdose crisis?",
      "answer": "Build the Wall, send National Guards to the border states and arrest the drug pushers!  Do Not catch and release !  Support President Trump on this issue!",
      "shortname": "Opioids"
    },
    {
      "question": "What if anything should the state do to address income inequality?",
      "answer": "There's going to be income inequality no matter what !  Income should be based on merits, educational level and experience , not on gender!",
      "shortname": "Income inequality"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do the state’s Public Information Act and open meetings laws adequately ensure Marylanders’ ability to exercise oversight of the government?",
      "answer": "More research needs to be done in this area.",
      "shortname": "Transparency"
    }
  ],
  "race": "state-senate",
  "residence": "West Deer Park Road",
  "sn1": "Kirwan",
  "sn10": "Opioids",
  "sn11": "Income inequality",
  "sn12": "Transparency",
  "sn2": "Transportation",
  "sn3": "Marijuana",
  "sn4": "Chesapeake Bay",
  "sn5": "Health Care",
  "sn6": "Crime",
  "sn7": "Business Climate",
  "sn8": "Redistricting",
  "sn9": "LEOBR",
  "survey-response": true,
  "title": "Josephine J. Wang"
}
